Lorenzo Rivosecchi

I'm a Web Developer with 6 years of experience in the field. I'm currently working at xtream srl as a Software Developer. I have a background in Electronic Music and my passions are Art, Technology and Design.



Have you noticed that this document looks like a Github README? That's because it is! You can find out more about how I built it here

Pinned Repositories

Skills

I'm a passionate coder with a strong interest in user experience and accessibility. Here are a few technologies I have worked with:

```
AWS Bash S CSS Debian Docker Firebase Git Github Gitlab GraphQL

HTML5 Next.js Node.js GopenAI Python React.js Ruby on Rails S Sanity S Shopify

TailwindCSS Three.js TypeScript Vercel Vite W Wordpress B tRPC
```

Experience

xtream srl (2024 - Present)

I work in the Digital Products team at xtream as a Frontend Developer. We design and develop digital products for our clients using cutting edge technology and applying data driven decisions.

Assist Digital (2023 - 2024)

I worked in the Advanced AI team at Assist Digital. My job involves working with crossfunctional teams to design and develop user interfaces. My stack includes React, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, Tanstack Query, Gitlab, Vite.

La Colonia (2019 - 2023)

I worked as a frontend developer on a wide range of projects. From marketing webistes to E-Commerce and interactive web applications. During my time at La Colonia I helped the company to optimize the development process by introducing new tools and deployment strategies. Here are a few examples of projects I worked on:

- https://akfc66.gr
- https://andreacaputo.com
- https://blackmed.invernomuto.info
- https://karlaotto.com
- https://veneziafc.it

Freelance (2022 - Present)

I have worked on a few projects as a freelance developer. Here are a few examples:

- https://eneatoldo.com
- https://eneatoldo.studio
- https://lacortedeimiracoli.it

Education

In april 2020 I have graduated from the Milan Conservatory with a Bachelor degree in Electronic Music. As part of my thesis I created a web application to play music with friends over the internet using Electron and SuperCollider. The project can be found here

Blog posts

I like to write about the things I learn. Here are a few examples:

- Custom OTP inputs are dumb. Here is how to build one.
- OAuth2 and AWS Cognito for Browser Extensions
- Using OpenAI to control an Ableton Live Session
- How to setup a Node for Max project with TypeScript
- ChatGPT clone with React Suspense and Streaming
- Better LLM Chatbots with React Suspense ©
- I Published my CV on NPM

- How to make a ChatBot using HTTP streaming with LangChain and Express
- The best way to fetch data from Sanity (using zod)
- Consuming Web Streams with useState, SWR and React Query
- Taming the HTML dialog with React and TailwindCSS
- Consuming Web Streams with useState, SWR and React Query
- SEO friendly infinite scroll for Shopify themes

Additional links

- My website
- My personal email
- My music
- My blog